<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arch on owlsly</title><link>https://owlsly94.github.io/tags/arch/</link><description>Recent content in Arch on owlsly</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owlsly94.github.io/tags/arch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Top 5 Linux Distros for Gaming: A Newbie’s Fast-Track</title><link>https://owlsly94.github.io/blog/gaming-distros/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owlsly94.github.io/blog/gaming-distros/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-truth-about-distros"&gt;The Truth About Distros&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s get one thing straight: &lt;strong&gt;Linux is Linux.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether you use Arch, Debian, or Fedora, the underlying technology that runs your games—the Kernel, Mesa drivers, and Proton—is largely the same. Once you understand how to use a package manager and distinguish between a &amp;ldquo;stable&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;rolling&amp;rdquo; release, the brand name on the boot screen becomes secondary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, for someone jumping over from Windows today, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend four hours configuring a window manager just to launch &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;. You want a system that is &lt;strong&gt;ready for war out of the box.&lt;/strong&gt; These 5 distributions respect your time by providing the best pre-configured gaming environments for newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Secret Sauce: Why Your Games Actually Run on Linux</title><link>https://owlsly94.github.io/blog/anticheat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owlsly94.github.io/blog/anticheat/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-death-of-windows-only"&gt;The Death of &amp;ldquo;Windows Only&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For decades, the world believed a lie: &lt;em&gt;If you want to game, you must use Windows.&lt;/em&gt; But today, you can open a Linux computer, click &amp;ldquo;Play&amp;rdquo; on a Windows-exclusive game like &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Elden Ring&lt;/em&gt;, and it just&amp;hellip; works. Sometimes, it even runs faster than it does on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How? Is Linux pretending to be Windows? Is it magic? No. It’s &lt;strong&gt;Translation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-the-translator-meet-wine"&gt;1. The Translator: Meet WINE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand how this works, imagine two people: &lt;strong&gt;Wayne (Windows)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Linus (Linux)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Ultimate Guide to Gaming on Arch Linux</title><link>https://owlsly94.github.io/blog/gaming/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owlsly94.github.io/blog/gaming/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve spent years on Windows, you’ve been taught that &amp;ldquo;gaming on Linux&amp;rdquo; is either a myth or a headache. But for those of us who grew up tinkering from our young days to the depths of the Arch Wiki, we know the truth. On Arch, you don&amp;rsquo;t just &amp;ldquo;run&amp;rdquo; games&amp;hellip; You optimize the entire environment for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an &lt;strong&gt;AMD CPU/GPU combo&lt;/strong&gt; and the right configuration, your Linux machine isn&amp;rsquo;t just a daily driver, it’s a high-performance monster machine that you actually own.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>