<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>owlsly</title><link>https://owlsly94.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on owlsly</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owlsly94.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Top 5 Linux Distros for Gaming: A Newbie’s Fast-Track</title><link>https://owlsly94.github.io/blog/gaming-distros/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owlsly94.github.io/blog/gaming-distros/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-truth-about-distros"&gt;The Truth About Distros&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s get one thing straight: &lt;strong&gt;Linux is Linux.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether you use Arch, Debian, or Fedora, the underlying technology that runs your games—the Kernel, Mesa drivers, and Proton—is largely the same. Once you understand how to use a package manager and distinguish between a &amp;ldquo;stable&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;rolling&amp;rdquo; release, the brand name on the boot screen becomes secondary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, for someone jumping over from Windows today, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend four hours configuring a window manager just to launch &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;. You want a system that is &lt;strong&gt;ready for war out of the box.&lt;/strong&gt; These 5 distributions respect your time by providing the best pre-configured gaming environments for newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://owlsly94.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owlsly94.github.io/about/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hi-im-owlsly"&gt;Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Owlsly.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a &lt;strong&gt;Linux System Administrator&lt;/strong&gt; with a background in web development. I’ve been in the tech world for over 6 years now—starting with 4 years as a freelance web dev before moving into the sysadmin space, where I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last 2+ years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a big believer in open-source and minimalist design. I like systems that are fast, clean, and actually make sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-i-do"&gt;What I do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my professional time is spent managing Linux systems, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t lost my love for building things on the web. I’m a bit of a tinkerer, so I’m constantly messing with my &lt;strong&gt;dotfiles&lt;/strong&gt; and trying to learn something new every day.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Empty</title><link>https://owlsly94.github.io/projects/empty/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owlsly94.github.io/projects/empty/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="project-overview"&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="features"&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tools-used"&gt;Tools Used&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why"&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/owlsly94/"&gt;View the Source Code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Ultimate Guide to Gaming on Arch Linux</title><link>https://owlsly94.github.io/blog/gaming/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owlsly94.github.io/blog/gaming/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve spent years on Windows, you’ve been taught that &amp;ldquo;gaming on Linux&amp;rdquo; is either a myth or a headache. But for those of us who grew up tinkering from our young days to the depths of the Arch Wiki, we know the truth. On Arch, you don&amp;rsquo;t just &amp;ldquo;run&amp;rdquo; games&amp;hellip; You optimize the entire environment for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an &lt;strong&gt;AMD CPU/GPU combo&lt;/strong&gt; and the right configuration, your Linux machine isn&amp;rsquo;t just a daily driver, it’s a high-performance monster machine that you actually own.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From 'Sluggish' to Supreme: My Journey to 100% Linux</title><link>https://owlsly94.github.io/blog/from-sluggish-to-supreme/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owlsly94.github.io/blog/from-sluggish-to-supreme/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We all have that one moment that changes how we see technology. For me, it happened by accident during my school practice at an electrotechnical high school. While some of my peers were heading to big public firms like Telekom, I ended up at a small, private PC service shop. That’s where I saw it: a system that looked &amp;ldquo;weird,&amp;rdquo; fast, and undeniably cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-catalyst-ubuntu-910"&gt;The Catalyst: Ubuntu 9.10&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, I was rocking an Asus K70. It was a decent machine, but Windows 7 felt like it was running through mud. After peppering the tech at the shop with a thousand questions, we took the plunge and installed Ubuntu 9.10 &amp;ldquo;Karmic Koala.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>